<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Tauana J. Cunha</title>
    <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Tauana J. Cunha</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Tauana Cunha {year}</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://tauanacunha.com/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in Science interns Maggie and Lamia extract DNA out of &lt;80 year-old museum specimens</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-wisinterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-wisinterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anthropology major Maggie Hassler and high-schooler Lamia Ait-Abdellah spent ~7 weeks with me at the Field Museum, learning how to program in R and successfully extracting DNA of historically-preserved museum specimens of snails. They gave a clear and engaging presentation at the Internship Symposium, and Lamia was award the Lynika Strozier Award!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fieldmuseum.org/about/employee-groups/women-science/field-museum-women-science-internships&#34;&gt;Women in Science Intership&lt;/a&gt; is a fantastic program supported by the Women&amp;rsquo;s Board of the Field Museum.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in Current Biology &amp; in the press: surprising loss of universal metazoan genes in parasitic hairworms</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-currbiol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-currbiol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever heard about crazy hairworms that infect insects and make them jump into water so the worm can get out and find mates?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we sequenced the first genomes of this entire phylum of animals, and learned that they are even weirder than we thought!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tauanajc/status/1681329665938530304?s=20&#34;&gt;Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt; for a cool summary of the research, and click on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/publication/cunha-2023-currbiol/&#34;&gt;PDF button here&lt;/a&gt; for the full text!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/995413?&#34;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; and press coverage by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnn.com/2023/07/18/world/horsehair-worms-parasites-missing-genes-scn/index.html&#34;&gt;CNN&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iflscience.com/host-manipulating-parasitic-worms-lack-genes-every-other-animal-has-69877&#34;&gt;IFLScience&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inverse.com/science/mind-controlling-parasitic-worm-missing-genes-found-all-animals&#34;&gt;Inverse&lt;/a&gt;; or google &amp;lsquo;hairworms&amp;rsquo; for many others!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New GBE paper on the genome of a penis worm (Priapulida)</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-priapulidgbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-priapulidgbe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/gbe/evad103&#34;&gt;paper in GBE&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snorkeling and scuba diving in the Canary Islands in search of snails and slugs</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-fieldcanaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-fieldcanaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Joined friend and collaborator Juan Moles and his lab for intense fieldwork in La Palma, Canary Islands. Cold water, but fantastic animals! Keep an eye out for the products of this research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New GBE paper on the gigantic genome of a velvet worm</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-onygbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-onygbe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/gbe/evad021&#34;&gt;paper in GBE&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper about the diversity of marine snails of the Maldives</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2023-diversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little while ago, Juan Moles and I flew all the way to the Maldives to survey the biodiversity of marine snails &amp;amp; slugs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the checklist of &amp;gt;100 species we collected, photographed, and barcoded. Take a look at this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tauanajc/status/1621662096260743174?s=20&#34;&gt;Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt; for more details and for pics of the most amazing animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And get the &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/d15020219&#34;&gt;free PDF of the paper&lt;/a&gt; to see all beautiful plates and the new species that are described.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grainger Bioinformatics Center grant</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-grainger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-grainger/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excited to start as a postdoc at the Field Museum of Natural History in Chicago!</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-fieldmuseum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-fieldmuseum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beautiful weather to celebrate the fresh start of my postdoctoral position at the Field Museum of Natural History!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exciting research is coming on gastropod phylogenies and the evolution of gastropod feeding mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plenary talk on molluscan genomics at the World Congress of Malacology in Munich</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-wcm-plenary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-wcm-plenary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was fantastic to finally meet colleagues and friends in person again at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wcm2022.bio.lmu.de/wcmslider3/index.html&#34;&gt;World Congress of Malacology&lt;/a&gt; in Munich, Germany! Kudos to the president and organizing committee for such a well-organized and fun meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recording of my plenary talk on molluscan genomics will soon be available, keep an eye out for a link here in the near future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join us in Brazil for the next WCM in 2025!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unitasmalacologica.org&#34;&gt;Council of Unitas Malacologica&lt;/a&gt; (Yasunori Kano, Bernhard Ruthensteiner, Lenita Tallarico, Gerhard Haszprunar, me, Gonzalo Giribet):
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/post/wcm2022-unitas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Unitas&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvard connection at the congress dinner (Jennifer Trimble, me, Juan Moles, Gonzalo Giribet):
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/post/wcm2022-harvard.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Harvard&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrating the students that received travel grants from Unitas to attend the meeting:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/post/wcm2022-travel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TravelAwards&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brazilian representation in Munich (Jesus Troncoso, Sthefane, Lenita Tallarico, Sonia Barbosa, me):
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/post/wcm2022-brazilian.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Brazilian&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congress dinner and award ceremony to best student poster and oral presentations:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/post/wcm2022-awards.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;StudentAwards&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/post/wcm2022-dinner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;StudentAwards&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>~1000 gastropod vouchers from my research in Panama are on the way to the Smithsonian National Museum of Natural History!</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-si-vouchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-si-vouchers/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New mentee María Sanchez is investigating a possible invasive species in Panama</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-maria-nerita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-maria-nerita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my fieldwork along the Pacific coast of Panama, I found a morphotype of &lt;em&gt;Nerita&lt;/em&gt; in multiple localities that closely resembles N. albicilla, a species native to the Indo-Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New STRI-SENACYT fellow María Sanchez is barcoding this and several other species of &lt;em&gt;Nerita&lt;/em&gt; from Panama to investigate whether this is indeed an invasive and from which Indo-Pacific population it originated. She is additionally adding the Panamanian diversity of this important intertidal genus to a world-wide phylogenetic framework, and testing whether morphometric data is informative is distinguishing local species.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the STRI station in Bocas del Toro</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-bocas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-bocas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before time runs out at the Smithsonian Tropical Research Institute, a visit to the beautiful station at Bocas del Toro! Snorkeling and exploring the leaf litter to survey for future projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st place at the Smithsonian photo contest, category &#39;Fellows doing science&#39;</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-stri-photo-contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-stri-photo-contest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://stri.si.edu/story/photo-contest&#34;&gt;winning photo&lt;/a&gt; and all other great shots by fellows and interns of the Smithsonian Tropical Research Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New MBE paper refuting the monophyly of Arachnida</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-mbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2022-mbe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our &amp;gt;500-species molecular and morphological phylogeny places horseshoe crabs among arachnids, and highlights a scenario of multiple events of colonization of land by chelicerates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msac021&#34;&gt;paper in Molecular Biology and Evolution&lt;/a&gt; for details, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2022/02/18/science/horseshoe-crabs-arachnids.html&#34;&gt;news coverage at the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;! Led by the amazing Sharma Lab (University of Wisconsin-Madison).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Syst Bio paper on phylogenomic conflict in vetigastropod snails</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2021-systbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2021-systbio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am ready to bet that you have some object or have seen one around made of mother-of-pearl, like a piece of jewelry, buttons, or house decoration. If you are nodding yes right now, you have had a piece of a shell from a vetigastropod in your hands - &lt;a href=&#34;https://lmgtfy.app/?q=abalone+shell&amp;amp;t=i&#34;&gt;google &amp;lsquo;abalone shell&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; for an example!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present a well resolved backbone phylogeny for this major lineage of marine gastropods, who dominated Paleozoic oceans. These ancient internal branches are hard to resolve! We find conflicting results in two deep splits of the tree, but as we demonstrate, this is not caused by ancient introgression nor by any of a variety of possible methodological errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/sysbio/syab071&#34;&gt;paper in Systematic Biology&lt;/a&gt; to learn more! With James Reimer (University of the Ryukyus) and Gonzalo Giribet (Harvard University).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SICB talk on population genomics of an endangered gastropod</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2021-sicb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2021-sicb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year the Society for Integrative and Comparative Biology is hosting talk recordings throughout January and February, so lot&amp;rsquo;s of time to catch up on diverse topics! Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://sicbannualmeeting.pathable.co/meetings/virtual/m5syzwSWPhTLr36t2&#34;&gt;my talk &amp;lsquo;Population connectivity of an endangered gastropod across the Mediterranean&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; and join the live Q&amp;amp;A and discussion for the Population Genetics and Phylogeography session on February 2, 12pm EST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/sicb2021-screenshot.pdf&#34; alt=&#34;SICB&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk at the XI Congreso Latinoamericano de Malacología (CLAMA)</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2020-xiclama/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2020-xiclama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great time interacting with the community of malacologists in Latin America at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xiclama.info&#34;&gt;XI CLAMA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out my talk in Spanish &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/VirtualClama/videos/1092747487850777?t=7769&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Datos genómicos para la filogenia de gasterópodos&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Seminar at STRI Science Talks</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2020-stri-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2020-stri-seminar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk at the SBE meeting</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2020-sbemeeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2020-sbemeeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In COVID-19 times, an amazing group of early career scientists stepped up to organize the first &lt;a href=&#34;https://sbemeeting.weebly.com&#34;&gt;Systematics, Biogeography and Evolution (SBE)&lt;/a&gt; virtual meeting. The program reached over 1200 atendees from all over the world, allowing participation of many who often cannot attend regular meetings due to financial or other restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most talks were further streamed live and are available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgGlkPp4jCoZoatnG2--RJA/featured&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out my invited talk to the symposium of Phylogenomics and Molecular Evolution: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/B7AUrtVMjpw?t=3097&#34;&gt;Congruence and Conflict in Phylogenomics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/sbe-phylogenomics.pdf&#34; alt=&#34;SBE&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/sbe-atendees.pdf&#34; alt=&#34;SBE&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/sbe-speakers.pdf&#34; alt=&#34;SBE&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GGI grant</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2020-ggi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2020-ggi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More about the Global Genome Initiative (GGI): &lt;a href=&#34;https://naturalhistory.si.edu/research/global-genome-initiative&#34;&gt;https://naturalhistory.si.edu/research/global-genome-initiative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use this grant to collect and send many species of marine gastropods from the Pacific side of Panama to the National Museum of Natural History in Washington DC. Importantly, we will sequence some of their genomes to support work on population genomics and connectivity of marine species.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoc at STRI</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2020-stri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2020-stri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arrived in Panama to stay for two years as a Postdoctoral Fellow at the Smithsonian Tropical Research Institute! Keep an eye out to learn more about the predictive power of life history strategies over the dispersal capacity of marine snails.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks at Unicamp and USP</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-usp-unicamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-usp-unicamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just visited Unicamp and USP and got to see so many friends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talks were at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioforumunicamp.blogspot.com/2019/08/tauana-junqueira-cunha-harvard.html&#34;&gt;Biofórum&lt;/a&gt; seminar series at Unicamp, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ecoencontros.ib.usp.br/pt/seminarios/anteriores.html&#34;&gt;EcoEncontros&lt;/a&gt; series at USP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Congress of Malacology</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-wcm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-wcm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year the World Congress of Malacology happened in the beautiful Monterey Bay area, in California. I gave a talk on our gastropod phylogeny, and a poster on the evolution of shell shape.
Also, my first dive in cold waters (10ºC!) was so worth it! Frizzle anemone, kelp forest, gumboot chitons, and most importantly, giant keyhole limpets and the beautiful jeweled topsnail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World malacologists:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/post/wcm2019-all.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;World malacologists&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(mostly former) Giribet Lab members happy after dives (Vanessa González, Gonzalo Giribet, me, Sarah Lemer):
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/post/wcm2019-giribetlab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Giribet Lab divers&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With frizzle anemone:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/post/wcm2019-anemone.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tauana and frizzle anemone&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REU undergrad Macy Petrula presents at the Leadership Alliance National Symposium!</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-macypetrula-lans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-macypetrula-lans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Macy Petrula successfully presented her poster at the Leadership Alliance National Symposium! Macy is an undergraduate from the California State University, Sacramento, and this Summer she was part of the first cohort of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reu.oeb.harvard.edu/2019-reu-participants-mentors-and-projects&#34;&gt;Research Experience for Undergraduates at the OEB department&lt;/a&gt; at Harvard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/Macy_poster.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;MacyPetrula&#34;&gt;
Macy proudly showing off her poster!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/Macy_Juan_Tau_poster.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MaldivianTeam&#34;&gt;
With REU research mentors Juan Moles and myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution meeting</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-evolution-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-evolution-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just arrived in Providence RI for the Evolution meeting. Tomorrow evening I will be presenting my work on vetigastropod fossils, on the evolution of their shell shape:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ExHallBC_14 - Poster 96&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who are not here, or would like to see it in further details later, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/post/poster-evo2019.png&#34; alt=&#34;poster-evo19&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD defended, SnailedIt!</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-phd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-phd-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am now Dr. Tauana Cunha!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to family, friends, colleagues and institutions that supported me and my work during the PhD, and to everyone that came for the public presentation. Celebrated in great style with an awesome snail cake by lab friends Caitlin Baker and Vanessa Knutson!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SNAILED IT! =D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/defense1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;defense&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/defense2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;defense&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/defense3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;defense&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/defense4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;defense&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fissurellidae phylogeny and biogeography in MPE</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-mpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-mpe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper we…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build a phylogeny for the diverse and widespread keyhole limpets, leading to updates in classification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;used fossil data to calibrate the tree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added geographical information to estimate their distribution through time!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/publication/cunha-2019-mpe/&#34;&gt;Get it here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gastropod phylogenomics in Proceedings B</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-proceedingsb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2019-proceedingsb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curious about how gastropods (snails, limpets and slugs) are related?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interested in phylogenomic methods applied to ancient and short internodes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2018.2776&#34;&gt;my new paper in Proceedings B&lt;/a&gt; with Gonzalo Giribet on understanding the gastropod tree of life!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First preprint of my PhD</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2018-preprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2018-preprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Celebrating halloween with the first preprint of my PhD: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/457770v1&#34;&gt;Deep gastropod relationships resolved&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out to see how different groups of snails, limpets and slugs are related to each other! And for some cool phylogenomics methods. Feedback welcome :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting European museums for fossils</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2018-museum-visits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2018-museum-visits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Returning after four weeks of visiting invertebrate paleontology collections at the Oxford University Museum of Natural History, the Natural History Museum in London, and the National Museum of Natural History in Paris! Work: photographing fossil shells from the Mesozoic and early Cenozoic. Thanks to all of the collection curators/managers, colleagues and friends that helped and made me company during this time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/paris_lapse.gif&#34; alt=&#34;paris_lapse&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/img_8247.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;equipment&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/oxford_lapse.gif&#34; alt=&#34;oxford_lapse&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faculty for the Future Fellowship!</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2018-fff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2018-fff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just got the wonderful news that my application was selected for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facultyforthefuture.net&#34;&gt;Faculty for the Future Fellowship&lt;/a&gt;! Recipients are women in STEM fields who may become role models in the sciences upon returning to their home countries. The fellowship will fund the last year of my PhD at Harvard, working with the phylogenetic relationships of gastropods, their biogeography in the marine environment and the evolution of shell shape across large time scales.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Award!</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2018-teaching-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2018-teaching-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a great semester with many leading researchers coming to talk to us about all sorts of topics and software on phylogeography and phylogenomics, I got the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bokcenter.harvard.edu/teaching-awards&#34;&gt;Certificate of Distinction in Teaching&lt;/a&gt; from the Derek Bok Center for my work at &amp;lsquo;Phylogenetics and Phylogeography in the Era of Genomics&amp;rsquo; (OEB275r) last Fall!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-school student Jesse Guerrero presents about his marine science internship!</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2017-jesseguerrero-crls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2017-jesseguerrero-crls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jesse Leon Guerrero gave a great presentation at the closing event of the Marine Science Internship Program! The program is a partnership between Harvard and the Cambridge Rindge and Latin School - read about &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2017/06/university-internships-push-students-in-new-directions/&#34;&gt;this year&amp;rsquo;s experiences at the Harvard Gazette&lt;/a&gt;. Jesse worked all semester photographing and measuring fossil shells, reading papers and analyzing data (see photos below). Now he is off to UMass Amherst!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/Jesse-camera.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JesseLeon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/news-projs/Jesse-fossils.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Fossils&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://tauanacunha.com/html/Jesse-3Dshellgraph.html&#34;
  title=&#34;3D graph fossil shells&#34;
  width=&#34;723&#34;
  height=&#34;723&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G4 Symposium</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2017-g4symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2017-g4symposium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In OEB-Harvard, all fourth year students present to the whole department in the G4 Symposium. It is one of the milestones of our program and everyone did so great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;G4cohort.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;G4cohort.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merit Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2017-merit-gsas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2017-merit-gsas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just found out that my application was selected for a Merit Fellowship from Harvard GSAS! (Award from the John Parker Bequest, 1873)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSF DDIG Award!</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2016-ddig/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2016-ddig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just got the awesome news that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=1701648&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&#34;&gt;my NSF DDIG&lt;/a&gt; was approved! Gastropod shell morphology, here we go!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Award</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2016-teaching-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2016-teaching-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got a second &lt;a href=&#34;https://bokcenter.harvard.edu/teaching-awards&#34;&gt;Certificate of Distinction in Teaching&lt;/a&gt; from the Derek Bok Center for my teaching of &amp;lsquo;Biology and Evolution of Invertebrate Animals&amp;rsquo; (OEB51) this last Spring. Another great semester with the most wonderful animals and great students!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSB Research Award</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2015-ssb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2015-ssb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just received the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.systbio.org/graduate-student-research-awards.html&#34;&gt;Graduate Student Research Award&lt;/a&gt; from the Society of Systematic Biologists! Let&amp;rsquo;s go, gastropods!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching award</title>
      <link>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2015-teaching-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 20:12:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tauanacunha.com/news/2015-teaching-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was awarded a &lt;a href=&#34;https://bokcenter.harvard.edu/teaching-awards&#34;&gt;Certificate of Distinction in Teaching&lt;/a&gt; from the Derek Bok Center for my teaching of &amp;lsquo;Biology and Evolution of Invertebrate Animals&amp;rsquo; (OEB51) in the Spring. It was a great semester with an enthusiastic group of students!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
